<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<changelogs>
        <changelog>
                <date>April 1, 2016</date>
                <heading>Data Sharing Agreements</heading>
                <news>
                        Some data collection sites are shown as gray dots on the map, indicating that data are not available for public display.
                        There are several possible reasons for this, but it may be that the contributor has not yet signed a data sharing agreement.
                        We encourage all states and other weather data contributors to sign such an agreement in order to provide a richer database
                        to our research community.
                </news>
                <url>/newsPage.jsp</url>
                <link>internal</link>
                <featured>true</featured>
	</changelog>
	<changelog>
                <date>May 12, 2016</date>
                <heading>WxDE Version 3.3</heading>
                <news>
                        The WxDE team is currently developing several system enhancements that will be available in version 3.3.
                        Map enhancements will improve performance and update control of various layers of information display.
                        We have also added three new quality checks and are implementing an inference module from the Vehicle Data Translator.
                </news>
                <url>/changeLog.jsp</url>
                <link>internal</link>
                <featured>true</featured>
        </changelog>
        <changelog>
                <date>April 25-27, 2016</date>
                <heading>Coming Up...</heading>
                <news>
 			International Conference on Winter Maintenance and Surface Transportation Weather, Fort Collins, CO.
                </news>
                <url>http://www.cvent.com/events/2016-international-conference-workshop-on-winter-maintenance-and-surface-transportation-weather/event-summary-68f0128fa8f541a7a72894d622be6b02.aspx</url>
                <link>external</link>
                <featured>true</featured>
        </changelog>
        <changelog>
                <date>April 27-29, 2016</date>
                <heading>Coming Up...</heading>
                <news>
			Standing International Road Weather Commission (SIRWEC) Conference, Fort Collins, CO.
                </news>
                <url>http://www.sirwec.org/</url>
                <link>external</link>
                <featured>true</featured>
        </changelog>
        <changelog>
                <date>June 28-30, 2016</date>
                <heading>Coming Up...</heading>
                <news>
                        2016 Road Weather Management Stakeholder Meeting, Atlanta, GA. The purpose of the meeting is to provide a venue for peer exchange 
			between the transportation and weather communities consisting of State Departments of Transportation, academia, vendors, 
			weather service providers (public and private), and consultants. The meeting will include presentations, facilitated discussions, 
			and networking opportunities for all participants.
                </news>
                <url>http://www.ops.fhwa.dot.gov/weather/</url>
                <link>external</link>
                <featured>true</featured>
        </changelog>
</changelogs>
